<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miami Real Estate Video Blog with Jorge Gonzalez</title>
    <description>Our mission at Team Dad of Eight is to be your best resource for Miami real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The Team Dad of Eight, your professional Miami Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 11:17:45 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 11:17:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>2 Upgrades That Aren’t Worth It</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kUZmv_b6Ots?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two home improvements are actually disasters for your investment in your property. These two “improvements” may bring you joy, but they won’t earn you more money when you sell the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Solar panels and impact-resistant windows.&lt;/strong&gt; You may see ads in home improvement magazines promoting the installation of these to increase your house’s value. These are wonderful things to install if you want them, but they truly don’t substantially increase your property’s value. There’s even excellent financing for solar panels and these special windows if you desire them, so you may think that you’ll get your money back from these when it’s time to sell. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These upgrades might be appealing to some homebuyers, but you probably won’t recapture your investment in them. Think about this carefully before installing solar panels or impact-resistant windows and doors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If you want a pool, I recommend buying a house that already has one.%20http://localhost:4000/2-upgrades-that-arent-worth-it.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If you want a pool, I recommend buying a house that already has one.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Pools.&lt;/strong&gt; Here in South Florida, we love pools, but they aren’t necessarily a great investment for your home. If you want a pool, I recommend buying a house that already has one—in Florida, there are many. Today, the minimum cost of building a pool is $30,000 to $40,000 for a basic pool. It’ll cost you even more if you add any extra features like a whirlpool spa, waterfalls, or LED lighting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most properties with pools only sell for an additional $10,000 to $20,000 at best. If you have a home with room for a pool and you absolutely want one, go ahead and build it because you’ll enjoy it with friends and family, but certainly not as an investment &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have further questions about today’s topic or anything else concerning real estate, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 11:31:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2-upgrades-that-arent-worth-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2-upgrades-that-arent-worth-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Which 2 Rooms Impact Your Sale the Most?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZxGb9vGFJHU?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan to invest any time, money, and effort into making your home more appealing, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll want to focus on two key areas: the kitchens and the bathrooms.&lt;/strong&gt; No matter what the house looks like as far as decor and style, an updated kitchen and bathroom will really pack a punch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s face it: When families gather together for parties or holidays, &lt;strong&gt;they tend to congregate in the kitchen area&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s why it’s very popular nowadays to have an open kitchen concept where the kitchen actually shares space with family rooms and living rooms to allow people to flow to and fro. For that same reason, kitchen islands are also widely sought-after.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=It’s very popular nowadays to have an open kitchen concept.%20http://localhost:4000/which-2-rooms-impact-your-sale-the-most.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“It’s very popular nowadays to have an open kitchen concept.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you update your kitchen, &lt;strong&gt;it doesn’t have to be with top-of-the-line materials and finishes.&lt;/strong&gt; By simply updating it with good, new materials that show off a modernized kitchen, you’ll get most of the money you spend back when you sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend that sellers &lt;strong&gt;go out and look at model homes in new developments&lt;/strong&gt;; that’s one way to see what currently appeals to homebuyers. Believe me, those builders invest a lot of money to investigate and research what buyers are looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same techniques that apply to the kitchen also apply to the bathrooms. Make some simple updates like new paint, tile, vanities, sinks, toilets, and/or tubs, and you’ll see the buyers come flocking to your listing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about readying your home to sell for the most on the market, don’t hesitate to reach out. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 13:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/which-2-rooms-impact-your-sale-the-most.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/which-2-rooms-impact-your-sale-the-most.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Sell a Home During the Pandemic</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/f27_m_vr3rg?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what’s going on in the world around us right now, some people need to sell their homes. With all the lockdown measures being taken across the country (and the world), you might wonder how selling a home would even be possible. Today I’ll share some key information you need to know about how to sell your home in the era of social distancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that most people are staying home, &lt;strong&gt;the real estate process has had to largely become a virtual transaction.&lt;/strong&gt; That affects how Realtors market homes. So what’s the new normal? Well, if everything is going online, that means that the online marketing tools we use have to be enhanced. Buyers need to be able to get a good feel of the house before actually going to look at the property. That necessitates three things if you want the best exposure for your property:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better photography&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Better videos&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A better virtual experience. 3D home tours, with the right tools, allow buyers to “walk through the house” online so they can see the property and all its corners. They can even allow buyers to take measurements of different spaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We make sure that buyers come to the house wearing proper face masks, gloves, and shoe covers.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-a-home-during-the-pandemic.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We make sure that buyers come to the house wearing proper face masks, gloves, and shoe covers.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showings have also had to change. For one, only serious buyers will be allowed to go to a showing. The new normal here involves &lt;strong&gt;thoroughly disinfecting the property before and after each showing and keeping in line with social distancing&lt;/strong&gt;; this is especially important if the property isn’t currently vacant. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also been going through the house to open all the interior doors. Why? &lt;strong&gt;So that we can instruct visiting buyers not to touch anything.&lt;/strong&gt; If everything is already open and available for inspection, there is no need for them to physically handle anything. Further, we do not shake hands or hug any of our clients. We also make sure that buyers come to the house wearing proper face masks, gloves, and shoe covers so as not to track anything into the home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do need to sell your house, don’t worry; &lt;strong&gt;right now is a great time to sell your home.&lt;/strong&gt; You can count on me to invest in the best measures to keep clients safe and healthy even as they finish their real estate transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t hesitate to reach out to me with any questions or needs you have. In the meantime, keep yourself and your loved ones safe!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 15:26:03 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-a-home-during-the-pandemic.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-sell-a-home-during-the-pandemic.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does the COVID-19 Cares Act Stimulus Plan Allow for You to Skip Mortgage Payments?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/79xMQr7XorE?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What will be the economic impact of the lockdown caused by the Coronavirus? How will this crisis affect YOU personally? The fact is that many people have already experienced a reduction in their income, and many more have or will lose their jobs and income altogether. You may be fearful about how you will make ends meet, and you are right to be concerned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a mortgage, I’m sure you’re wondering &lt;strong&gt;how you will be able to make your monthly payment.&lt;/strong&gt; Recently a relief bill was approved by Congress and signed by the President. The federal government’s stimulus bill, called the CARES Act, includes a feature allowing homeowners to skip mortgage payments without penalties. Traditionally, skipping your mortgage payments due to a hardship is done through what’s called a forbearance, which has its pros and cons to be careful with; the CARES Act allows for payment deferrals which may be a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional links that may be helpful:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.knowyouroptions.com/options-to-stay-in-your-home/overview/forbearance&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.knowyouroptions.com/options-to-stay-in-your-home/overview/forbearance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.investopedia.com/how-to-get-mortgage-relief-4800539&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.investopedia.com/how-to-get-mortgage-relief-4800539&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.consumerfinance.gov/ask-cfpb/what-is-forbearance-en-289/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;https://www.consumerfinance.gov/ask-cfpb/what-is-forbearance-en-289/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions relating to your mortgage, or how the real estate market is faring, don’t hesitate to reach out by phone or email at any time. We’re always here to help, no matter your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 16:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/does-the-covid-19-cares-act-stimulus-plan-allow-for-you-to-skip-mortgage-payments.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/does-the-covid-19-cares-act-stimulus-plan-allow-for-you-to-skip-mortgage-payments.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Should You Remodel Your Home Before Selling?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DuuBYx72wiI?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever thought about selling your house, but think that you need to do some work to it before you sell? Today we’re talking about the pros and cons of making improvements and remodels on your home before you sell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times, Realtors will encourage you to do some staging, which is a term for making your property look the best it can so you can get the highest price. Staging requires careful planning, and &lt;strong&gt;if your house is dated compared to what else is on the market, you’ll need to start the planning early. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realtors are generally happy to advise you to make any and every repair because that makes the property easier to sell. However, it’s not always in your best interest. I take a more consultative approach. The top price isn’t actually what matters. &lt;strong&gt;What really matters is what you net at the end of the transaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We want you to walk away with the highest net profit possible.%20http://localhost:4000/should-you-remodel-your-home-before-selling.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We want you to walk away with the highest net profit possible.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen sellers spend $20,000 renovating their kitchen, but only sold their home for $10,000 more than they could have if they didn’t do anything. That’s a net loss. We don’t want that to happen to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You need to know which home improvements are going to increase your ROI and your bottom line.&lt;/strong&gt; The focus is not on the highest sale price, it’s on the highest net profit from the sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you may just need some light enhancements and some deep cleaning. There are plenty of inexpensive things you can do to enhance your home’s value. I’ve seen many cases where a seller spends a lot of money and fixes up their house, but it’s not what the market likes. That’s another mistake you can avoid with careful planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about selling your home but you’re not sure what you need to do to prepare it, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email today. I’d be happy to meet with you and discuss your personal situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 15:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/should-you-remodel-your-home-before-selling.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/should-you-remodel-your-home-before-selling.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What You Need to Know About Homestead Exemptions</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/drJxvE4Qi3Q?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a homeowner living in the state of Florida, you can file for a homestead exemption. &lt;strong&gt;This means you can save on your property taxes,&lt;/strong&gt; but you have to file for this exemption to take advantage of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you buy a house, you only have to file once. After that, you have the exemption as long as the house is your primary residence. If you buy a home with me, I’ll send you a reminder to file at the beginning of the year after you bought it. You have to be timely, though, because there’s a deadline to file for the previous year’s exemption, and that deadline in Miami and Broward County is March 1. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you bought a house last year, it’s your primary residence, and you’ve been living in it since January 1 of 2020, you qualify for the homestead exemption. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There’s a deadline to file for the previous year’s exemption, and that deadline in Miami and Broward County is March 1.%20http://localhost:4000/what-you-need-to-know-about-homestead-exemptions.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There’s a deadline to file for the previous year’s exemption, and that deadline in Miami and Broward County is March 1.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much does it save on your property taxes? The homestead exemption is always worth $50,000, so if your home’s assessed value is $300,000, you’d only be taxed for $250,000. Depending on your municipality within the county, that could be a substantial amount since you’re carrying that exemption for however long you stay in the house. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some situations, it’s a prerequisite for people to apply for additional exemptions. If you’re a widower with a homestead exemption, you’ll be eligible for additional benefits, as is also the case for blind people and disabled veterans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are all kinds of exemptions you can qualify for, so if you’d like to know more, use the following links to file for your homestead exemption:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.miamidade.gov/Apps/PA/PAOnlineTools/AutoOnlineFile/ExemptionOnlineMainMenu.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Miami-Dade County&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://bcpasecure.net/homesteadonline/web/index.aspx&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Broward County&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you don’t file by March 1, you have to wait until 2021 and miss out on a whole year’s worth of savings.&lt;/strong&gt; I don’t want that happening to you, so if you have questions about this topic, don’t hesitate to call or email me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, if you have any other real estate needs, feel free to reach out to me as well. I’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 15:37:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-you-need-to-know-about-homestead-exemptions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-you-need-to-know-about-homestead-exemptions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Interest Rates Affect Buying &amp; Selling in 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/DwG2fCD5R0E?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the federal funds rate and why is it always talked about so much? How does it impact you as a buyer or seller?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The federal funds rate is basically an interest rate charged between banks when they lend each other money overnight. This is an important rate because it’s guided and set by the Federal Reserve. A lot of people assume that when the federal funds rate goes up or down, mortgage rates follow suit. The truth, though, is that rarely happens. The federal funds rate rarely has a direct impact on mortgage rates. Sometimes, they go in opposite directions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in knowing what mortgage rates will do and how that will affect your buying or selling plans, &lt;strong&gt;the 10-Year Treasury note is the rate you want to follow.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s a short-term rate that pays interest at a fixed rate once every six months, and it ties in almost exactly with where mortgage rates for a 30-year loan will be. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s interesting about this is when interest rates are expected to rise, people assume home prices might fall. That’s possible—unless your mortgage rate is pretty low, you probably don’t like to hear that mortgage rates are going up. However, if you’re thinking about buying another house and want to sell your current one, that house suddenly becomes less affordable to buyers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The federal funds rate rarely has a direct impact on mortgage rates.%20http://localhost:4000/how-interest-rates-affect-buying-selling-in-2020.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The federal funds rate rarely has a direct impact on mortgage rates.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, when mortgage rates drop, people get excited because they think they can afford a house, so more buyers rush the market. That demand boosts home prices, and since existing buyers think they can afford higher-priced homes, that increases prices even further. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you’re a seller, should you sell in 2020 or stay put? I’ll say this: &lt;strong&gt;There is a likelihood that interest rates for mortgages creep up&lt;/strong&gt;, because lenders are dying to push rates up a little bit. Don’t pay much attention to the federal funds rate, though. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to talk more about your goals for 2020 and whether it’s best to sell now or later, give me a call. We’ll examine the micro-trends of your specific marketplace and decide what’s best. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 11:46:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-interest-rates-affect-buying-selling-in-2020.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-interest-rates-affect-buying-selling-in-2020.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle a Multiple-Offer Situation as a Seller</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/pM_7ViOH_xc?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigating a multiple-offer situation as a seller is always a nice problem to have. In those situations, my job as the Realtor is to first notify the seller that there are multiple offers on the table. From there, we have a couple of options for how to handle the buyers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could simply choose an offer we like and accept it, but we want to see if that offer was really the buyer’s best one. We can’t really respond to more than one offer because of the possibility that more than one buyer will accept your counteroffer (naturally, you can’t go around promising one house to multiple people). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=An auction atmosphere really creates a fervor that causes people to bid higher than they ever thought they would.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-a-multiple-offer-situation-as-a-seller.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“An auction atmosphere really creates a fervor that causes people to bid higher than they ever thought they would.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make sure each buyer is putting their best foot forward, &lt;strong&gt;we inform all of them that the seller is welcoming the buyers’ final and best offers, which must be submitted within 24 hours.&lt;/strong&gt; This essentially initiates a silent bid amongst the buyers. An auction atmosphere really creates a fervor that causes people to bid higher than they ever thought they would. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the time frame is up and we’ve received each buyer’s final and best offer, we can start the decision-making process. We’ll sit down with you and scrutinize every offer. Remember, you can even counter the highest offer among all of those final offers. Maybe you want to try to refine some of the terms involved—you always have that power. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whatever the case, I’ll be there as your partner, making sure we take advantage of the best strategy to get top dollar for your property.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re thinking of selling your house, feel free to reach out to me. Let’s sit down, check out the data, review the market conditions, and see how I can get you the highest price for your home in the quickest amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 14:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-a-multiple-offer-situation-as-a-seller.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-a-multiple-offer-situation-as-a-seller.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Handle Multiple Offers as a Buyer</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zxj3JLNHjms?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a buyer faced with a situation where you know there’s a big buzz about a house you’re interested in, you may be looking at a multiple-offer situation. How should you proceed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently working with some clients who were looking to make the leap to homeownership. After two months, we found the perfect home for them. When they finally saw the property in person, there was a huge crowd at the open house. &lt;strong&gt;I told them at that point there would probably be multiple offers on the property, so we need to put our best foot forward in the initial offer. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=A low appraisal gives buyers more negotiation power.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-multiple-offers-as-a-buyer.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“A low appraisal gives buyers more negotiation power.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a situation like this, a lowball offer simply won’t work. Somebody is going to offer the full price, and maybe even offer above it. However, a full-priced offer won’t always work. Sometimes you’ll need to be generous on terms or offer more than the asking price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a seller’s market like this, I always recommend this strategy to get the property under contract.&lt;/strong&gt; Once it’s under contract, there are certain places where we can negotiate to get you a little bit better deal. One example is a low appraisal, which gives us a lot more negotiation power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are in the market to buy a house and you’re confronted with a situation like this, give me a call or send me an email. I’d be happy to share my experience to guide you through the process of becoming a homeowner. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 10:34:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-multiple-offers-as-a-buyer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-handle-multiple-offers-as-a-buyer.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What’s the Difference Between a Buyer’s Market and a Seller’s Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/m3MGkKmLPEM?rel=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever people ask me how the market is, I always tell them the same thing: It depends. Specifically, it depends on whether you’re buying or selling. If you’re selling, it depends how your home is priced. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Real estate is local. In fact, I would call it sub-local. What’s the difference between a buyer’s market and a seller’s market, then? &lt;strong&gt;A buyer’s market simply means buyers have more control, and a seller’s market means sellers have more control.&lt;/strong&gt; There are several important statistics agents look at to distinguish one from the other. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first metric is &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;homes’ average days on market,&lt;/strong&gt; or how long properties in a specific neighborhood stay on the market before going under contract. If the average is short, that’s an indication of a seller’s market. If the average is long, that means buyers have more control. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If a lot of sellers are lowering the prices on their homes, it means they’re trying to entice buyers, which is a sure sign of a buyer’s market.%20http://localhost:4000/whats-the-difference-between-a-buyers-market-and-a-sellers-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If a lot of sellers are lowering the prices on their homes, it means they’re trying to entice buyers, which is a sure sign of a buyer’s market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also look at the &lt;strong&gt;absorption rate&lt;/strong&gt; (aka inventory), which measures how long it would take to sell all available homes on the market if no new homes were listed. If the absorption rate is five months or less, it’s considered a seller’s market. Six months is considered a balanced market. Anything higher than that is considered a buyer’s market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another factor I keep an eye on is &lt;strong&gt;price movement on the MLS.&lt;/strong&gt; If a lot of sellers are lowering the prices on their homes, it means they’re trying to entice buyers, which is a sure sign of a buyer’s market. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to know what your home is worth or whether you’re in a buyer’s or seller’s market, give me a call and I’d be happy to run the numbers for you. If you have any other real estate questions, feel free to reach out to me as well. I look forward to hearing from you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 12:41:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-the-difference-between-a-buyers-market-and-a-sellers-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-the-difference-between-a-buyers-market-and-a-sellers-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
